<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!-- TAGS SHOULD BE SEPARATED BY SPACES-->

<!-- LINKS IN THE BODY TEXT SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;a href="ADDRESS">NAME&lt;/a> -->
<!-- LINE BREAKS SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;br> -->

<resources>
    <string-array name="pits_design">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Pit Design</item>
        <item>Designing your pit is one of the most important things to do before you head to
            competition. Creating your pit is not something to take lightly considering it
            represents your team in the pits at competitions. There are many different aspects to
            consider when designing your teams pit. One main thing to think about is implementing
            your team\'s name and number into your pit. Your name and number should be clearly visible
            to everyone whether they are judges, other team members/mentors, or volunteers; it is
            very important that your pit is noticeable to all of these people.
            &lt;br>The design of your pit is also supposed to not only display your teams name and
            number but also your teams theme and values. Judges are constantly in the pits so it is
            important that your team’s values are displayed openly. This can be shown by hanging up
            posters, displaying your sponsors names, or even banners. Hanging a banner across the
            top of your pit is an easy way to display a lot of information that can easily be seen
            by everyone. As you can see, there are many ways to show your teams theme and values in
            your pit design. The best advice we can give is to have fun and be creative!</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_designSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Diseño de los Pits</item>
        <item>Diseñar el pit es una de las cosas mas importantes de hacer antes de dirigirse a la
competencia. La creación del pit es algo que no se debe tomar a la ligera, ya que deben
considerar que es lo que representa a tu equipo en los pits durante la competencia. Existen
varios aspectos que deben considerar mientras diseñen el pit de su equipo. El nombre de su
equipo, así como su numero, debe estar en un punto donde todos lo puedan ver, tanto
miembros o mentores de otros equipos como jueces y voluntarios; es muy importante que su
nombre se de a notar. Los jueces están de manera constante en los pits, entonces es muy
importante que estén los valores de su equipo estén a la vista. La mejor manera de hacerlo
es colgando posters con los logos de sus patrocinadores o incluso banderines a colocados
en la parte superior de su pit, que es una muy buena manera de mostrar una gran cantidad
de información para que todos la puedan ver. Como pueden ver, hay muchas maneras de
mostrar el tema de su equipo y sus valores en el diseño del pit. El mejor consejo que les
podemos dar es que se diviertan y sean creativos!</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_organization">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Organization</item>
        <item>Organization is one of the most important things in your team’s pit. Without a system
            of organization it is almost inevitable that you will lose something. There are many
            different ways to organize your pit. You will have a ton of tools and items you will be
            bringing with you that will all seem to end up in your pit. It is a good idea to have
            boxes, cabinets, etc. so items are not lost or stolen. Organizing your pit crew\'s tools
            is a vitally important thing for your team’s success because if your robot breaks during
            competition you want to be able to find these tools easily. It is also important to leave
            tools that are commonly needed during competition in a close by place so they can be accessed easily.
            &lt;br>Aside from the tools there are many other things that will need to be organized
            in your pit whether they are computers, batteries, or even jackets. It is a good idea
            to have an easily accessible area with the batteries so you can quickly change them when
            necessary. Computers are not something you likely want to leave out in the open, even if
            there is someone always in your pit, it is best to put them in a safe place such as a
            cabinet or even just under a table out of site. Jackets and other such items can easily
            be put into a box or crate so they are not taking up space inside the pit. Lastly, always
            remember to leave space to work when needed.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_organizationSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Organización</item>
        <item>La organización es un de las cosas más importantes en el pit de su equipo. Sin un sistema
de organización, es casi inevitable que pierdan algo. Existen varias maneras para organizar
su pit. Van a tener muchas herramientas y objetos que van a traer y acabarán de alguna
manera u otra en su pit. Es una buena idea traer cajas, un mueble con cajones, etc. para que
los objetos no se pierdan o se los roben. Organizar las herramientas del equipo del pit es de
vital importancia para el éxito de su equipo, ya que si su robot se descompone durante la
competencia les conviene tener las herramientas que van a necesitar a la mano. También es
importante tener a la mano las herramientas que utilizan frecuentemente. Además de las
herramientas, hay otras cosas que necesitan mantener organizadas en su pit, como
computadoras, baterías o incluso chamarras. Es una buena idea designar un espacio de
acceso fácil con baterías para poder cambiarlas rápidamente cuando sea necesario. Las
computadoras son algo que no van a querer dejar al descubierto, aun cuando haya siempre
alguien es su pit, así que lo mejor sería dejarlos en un lugar seguro como un gabinete o
abajo de una mesa. Las chamarras y otros objetos de ese estilo se pueden guardar en una
caja para que no ocupen espacio dentro del pit. Por ultimo, recuerden siempre dejar espacio
libre para poder trabajar cuando sea necesario.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_crew">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Pit Crew</item>
        <item>The pit crew are some of the most crucial people off the field. It is important to
            allow them the space necessary in the pit for immediate work and for those moments of
            rushed panic. The pit crew should be ready for anything at any time. The crew should be
            about 5-6 people so there is not too few or too many people in the pits. The pits can
            easily get crowded so it is important to not have too many people around so there is
            plenty of space to work on the robot. With the drive team and the pit crew constantly
            in and out of the pits it’s important to keep a minimal amount of people besides them in
            the area to avoid overcrowding. A last reminder, it is very important to have mechanical
            people in the pit crew, but a programmer is just as necessary for a successful robot.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_crewSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Equipo de Pit</item>
        <item>El equipo de pit son de la personas mas cruciales fuera del campo. Es importante dejarles el
espacio necesario dentro del pit para trabajo inmediato o momentos de pánico. El equipo de
pit debe estar preparado para cualquier cosa en cualquier momento. El equipo debe estar
compuesto de 5-6 personas para que no haya gente de más o gente de menos en los pits.
Con el equipo de manejo y el equipo de pits entrando y saliendo constantemente, es
importante mantener la menor cantidad de gente posible para que haya suficiente espacio
para el robot, ya que pits se pueden llenar de gente fácilmente. Un último recordatorio, es
que es muy importante que haya mecánicos que seas parte del equipo de pit, pero un
programador es igual de necesario para tener un robot exitoso.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_judges">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Talking With Judges</item>
        <item>Talking with judges is obviously one of the most important parts of the pits. Judges
            are constantly walking through the pits at competitions so don’t forget to always show
            gracious professionalism. When judges come and talk to teams in the pits they are truly
            curious and eager to learn about your team and your robot. The judges will ask questions
            that are either relevant to your robot or your team so it is wise to have experts of both
            in your pits. When talking to judges always be informative. It is also important that
            when judges come to your team’s pit that a team member is doing most or all of the
            talking, not a mentor or parent. The judges are there to talk to the team, not the
            mentors.
            &lt;br>While the majority of the questions asked in the pit will be about your team\'s
            robot the judges will also be looking for contenders for the other awards at the
            competition. This will be even amplified if you are competing for the Chairman\'s award.
            It is important to have an expert on your team’s outreach, marketing, and fundraising
            side of your team in the pits as well. They will help answer these questions for the
            judges. Judges are also not the only ones coming to talk in the pits; you will have pit
            scouters, alliance partners, and volunteers always coming by also. Remember to always
            be in a good mood!</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="pits_judgesSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Plática con los Jueces</item>
        <item>Hablar con los jueces obviamente es una de las partes mas importantes de los pits. Los
jueces siempre están caminando por los pits, así que no olviden siempre mostrar ‘gracious
professionalism’. Cuando los jueces se acerquen a hablar con los equipos en los pits, tienen
verdadera curiosidad y ganas de conocer a al equipo y su robot. Los jueces van a hacer
preguntas sobre cosas relevantes sobre el robot o el equipos, así que es sabio tener a gente
experta en ambos en los pits. Cuando estés platicando con los jueces siempre sean
informativos. También es importante que cuando los jueces se acerquen a su pit que un
alumno esta haciendo toda o casi toda la platica, no un mentor o un papá. Los jueces están
ahí para platicar con el equipo, no los mentores. Aunque la mayoría de las preguntas que
hacen en el pit son su robot, los jueces también están buscando contendientes para los
demás premios de la competencia. Esta se va a amplificar si están compitiendo por un
premio Chairman’s. Es importante tener un experto en el ‘outreach’, marketing y fundraising
de su equipo en los pits también. Ellos les ayudarán a contestar estas preguntas a los jueces.
Los jueces no son los únicos que van a ir a babar con ustedes en los pits; van a tener ‘pit
scouters’, compañeros de alianza y voluntarios siempre visitando. Recuerden siempre estar
de buen humor!</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>
</resources>