<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!-- TAGS SHOULD BE SEPARATED BY SPACES-->

<!-- LINKS IN THE BODY TEXT SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;a href="ADDRESS">NAME&lt;/a> -->
<!-- LINE BREAKS SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;br> -->

<resources>
    <string-array name="early_programming">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Getting Started Programming</item>
        <item>In order to test your robot, you need to be able to control it. Start with the basics,
            and begin programming one subsystem at a time. It is important to remember that you
            shouldn\'t worry about perfecting the code at this time; save the fine-tuning and control
            loops for later. As long as you can control the subsystems at this point, and are able to
            read from any sensors that you might have, you\'re doing fine.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="early_programmingSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Programación Inicial</item>
        <item>Para poder probar su robot, necesitan poder controlarlo. Empiezan con lo básico, y empeoren
programando un subsistema a la vez. Es importante recordar que no es importante que no deben
preocuparse por perfeccionar el código en este momento, guarden la afinación y vueltas de control
para el final. Por ahora, mientras puedan controlar el subsistema y sean capaces de obtener lecturas
de los sensores que estén usando van bien.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="finishing_electrical">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Finishing Electrical</item>
        <item>This is the time for your electrical department to have finished your wiring. It is
            imperative that it is done so that your team will have as much time as possible for driving practice.
            Some tips for a successful season are:
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tDouble check all wire connections and make sure that they are
            secure, even one wire coming loose could mean your entire robot shutting off.
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tMake sure your power distribution board has fuses of the proper
            amperage placed in their respective slots to prevent damaging any electrical components.
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tIt is strongly recommended that all points of connection are
            labeled from one point to another, this can save huge amounts of time when trying to
            diagnose electrical problems.
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tIf nothing else, make sure your electrical is neat and tidy in
            its final form. It looks more impressive to the judges, and makes fixing things way more easy.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="finishing_electricalSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Terminando la Parte Eléctrica</item>
        <item>This is the time for your electrical department to have finished your wiring. It is
            imperative that it is done so that your team will have as much time as possible for driving practice.
            Some tips for a successful season are:
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tDouble check all wire connections and make sure that they are
            secure, even one wire coming loose could mean your entire robot shutting off.
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tMake sure your power distribution board has fuses of the proper
            amperage placed in their respective slots to prevent damaging any electrical components.
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tIt is strongly recommended that all points of connection are
            labeled from one point to another, this can save huge amounts of time when trying to
            diagnose electrical problems.
            &lt;br>&lt;br>&#8226;\tIf nothing else, make sure your electrical is neat and tidy in
            its final form. It looks more impressive to the judges, and makes fixing things way more easy.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

</resources>