<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!-- TAGS SHOULD BE SEPARATED BY SPACES-->

<!-- LINKS IN THE BODY TEXT SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;a href="ADDRESS">NAME&lt;/a> -->
<!-- LINE BREAKS SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;br> -->

<resources>
    <string-array name="scouting_match">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Match Scouting</item>
        <item>One of the most essential roles in a team at competition is scouting. Observing other
            robots during matches will help your team make decisions about alliance partners, as
            well as provide inspiration for any future changes to your strategy. Your team should
            look for other robots that are compatible with your own – having three identical robots
            on the same team probably isn\'t the best strategy. Even if your team is not going to be
            an alliance captain it is important that you keep scouting; if your team is picked your
            alliance partners may turn to you for help picking the third robot and for strategy.
            Scouting in the stands is designed to give your team as much information as possible
            about the performance of other robots. Your team can record both qualitative and
            quantitative information, but should have a standardized system for recording information.
            &lt;br>On-the-field performance depends on more than just the robot, it also depends
            on the driver. Have your scouting crew look at how other teams perform under stress,
            and make note of any flaws in their strategy that your team can exploit.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="scouting_matchSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Scouting en los partidos</item>
        <item>Hacer scouting es uno de los roles mas esenciales durante la competencia. Observar a otros
robots durante la competencia le ayudara a su equipo a tomar decisiones sobre sus aliados,
así como ser una fuente de inspiración para cualquier cambio a que vayan a hacer a su
estrategia. Su equipo debe buscar a robots que sean compatibles con el suyo - tener tres
robots idénticos en un mismo equipo probablemente no sea la mejor estrategia. Aun cuando
su equipo no vaya a ser capitán de una alianza, es importante seguir con el scouting; si su
equipo es elegido, sus aliados pueden pedirles ayuda para seleccionar un tercer robot o una
estrategia. Scouting en las gradas esta diseñado para darle a su equipo la mayor cantidad de
información posible a su equipo sobre los demás robots. Su equipo puede anotar información
cualitativa y cuantitativa, pero debe tener un sistema estandarizado para hacerlo. En la
cancha, el desempeño no sólo depende en el robot, también en el conductor. Hagan que su
equipo de scouting se fije en como se desempeñan otros equipos cuando están bajo estrés,
y anoten cualquier falla en su estrategia de la cual ustedes se puedan aprovechar.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="scouting_pits">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Pit Scouting</item>
        <item>Pit scouting is a great way to see every robot up close. You are able to see specifics
            of the robot\'s design and also some features not necessarily apparent on the field. As a
            team you should record important details such as the weight, height, drive-train and
            scoring capabilities. While pit scouting can\'t give you information about on the field
            performance, it can give your team an idea of what robots to look out for and what robots
            to consider for specialty purposes, such as pushing opponents out of the way. Make sure
            to take pictures of each robot to help connect each team with their robot.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="scouting_pitsSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Scouting en los Pits</item>
        <item>Hacer scouting en los pits es una muy buena manera de ver a todos los robots de cerca. Les
permite ver cosas específicas del diseño del robot así como cosas que no son aparentes en
la cancha. Como equipo, deben registrar detalles importantes como la altura, peso, ‘drive-
train’, y capacidad para anotar. Mientras que hacer scouting en los pits no les puede
proporcionar mucha información sobre el desempeño en la cancha del robot, les puede dar
una idea de que robots mantener en cuenta y cuales considerar para situaciones especiales,
como empujar a contrincantes por ejemplo. Asegúrense de tomar fotos de todos los robots
para poder hacer la conexión entre los equipos y sus robots.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>
</resources>