<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!-- TAGS SHOULD BE SEPARATED BY SPACES-->

<!-- LINKS IN THE BODY TEXT SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;a href="ADDRESS">NAME&lt;/a> -->
<!-- LINE BREAKS SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;br> -->

<resources>
    <string-array name="preparing_for_next_year">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Preparing for Next Year</item>
        <item>After the competition season ends, everyone deserves a rest, but there is still a lot
            of work to do. Your team must decide what you will be doing with your robot. Maybe it
            performed so well in competition that you want to keep it in operating conditions for
            demonstrations, or teaching new members about your robot. Maybe you will want to take it
            all apart so you can reuse parts for next year’s robot. Either way, your workspace
            probably could use some cleanup and organization of tools and parts after the last six
            weeks of mayhem. As your team grows it is important to keep up on the organization of
            your workspace to facilitate safety and productivity, as well as avoid the expense of
            having to replace lost tools or robot parts.
            &lt;br>If your team seeks to compete for the chairman’s award next year, you have more
            work to do. Demonstrations in your community during the summer goes a long way towards
            a convincing judges of your teams’ positive impact. If you kept your robot in operating
            condition, all the better. It will be your greatest tool for attracting positive interest
            in your robotics team, and to promote FIRST. KING TeC showcases their robot in an annual
            town parade in August, and brings it to schools for demonstrations in the fall and spring.
            &lt;br>How will you attract the most talented kids for your team next year? September
            is the best month to begin promoting your team to potential new members. Even though
            the FRC game isn’t released until January, there is a steep learning curve to follow if
            your new members want to learn all there is to know about an FRC robot, how the
            competitions work, and building skills. KING TeC makes it a priority that all our members
            are familiar with operating the power tools and the proper safety procedures to follow.
            Senior members can host classes in CAD or programming for the new members to learn essential
            software skills that will reap benefits during the competition season.
            &lt;br>To prepare new students for the intense atmosphere of first robotics competitions,
            consider using last years’ robot to compete at a mock regional in the fall. Older teams
            host small scale unofficial competitions in their high schools in the fall in order to
            train new members for the roles they will have at an actual competition. In Minnesota,
            KING TeC hosts the Minne-mini regional at their high school, where around 30 teams compete
            for a day. Search the Chief Delphi forums for practice competitions in your area.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="preparing_for_next_yearSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Preparándose para el siguiente año.</item>
        <item>Después de que la competencia termina, todos merecen un descanso, pero sigue habiendo
mucho trabajo por hacer. Tu equipo debe decidir lo que harán con su robot. Quizás se
comportó muy bien en las competencias y lo quieren mantener funcional para dar
demostraciones, o enseñarle a nuevos integrantes acerca del robot. De cualquier manera, tu
lugar de trabajo podrías tener una limpieza y reorganización de la herramienta después de
las seis semanas de ajetreo. Mientras que el equipo crece es importante mantener la
organización de tu espacio de trabajo para facilitar la seguridad y productividad, así como
laos gastos de tener que reponer partes perdidas. Si tu equipo pretende participar por el
Chairman’s Award el próximo año, tienes muchas cosas que hacer. Las demostraciones a tu
comunidad durante el verano van a la par con la comunicación a los jueces sobre el impacto
positivo del equipo en su comunidad. Si mantienes a tu robot en operación es mucho mejor.
Será la mejor herramienta para atraer interés positivo en tu equipo de robótica, y promover
FIRST. El equipo KING TeC muestra su robot en el desfile anual que se lleva a cabo en
Agosto, y trae a escuelas a demostraciones durante el otoño y la primavera. ¿Cómo atraerás
a las personas más talentosas a tu equipo el próximo año? Septiembre es el mejor momento
para empezar a promover el equipo a los posibles nuevos integrantes. Aunque el juego de
FRC no es anunciado sino hasta enero, hay una importante curva de aprendizaje que se
debe seguir si los nuevos integrantes quieren aprender acerca de todo lo que involucra a un
robot de FRC, cómo funcionan las competencias y habilidades de construcción. El equipo
KING Tec tiene como prioridad que todos los miembros de su equipo se familiaricen con las
herramientas y los procedimientos de seguridad a seguir. Los integrantes veteranos pueden
dar clases sobre CAD o programación a los nuevos integrantes para aprender las habilidades
esenciales de software que les darán mucho beneficio durante la temporada de competencia.
Para preparar a los estudiantes para la intensa atmósfera de las competencias de robótica
FIRST, considera usar el robot del año pasado para hacer un regional de prueba en el otoño.
Los equipos veteranos realizan algunas competencias extra-oficiales en sus escuelas para
entrenar a los nuevos estudiantes en los papeles que tendrán en la verdadera competencia.
En Minnesota, el equipo KING TeC lleva a cabo el regional ‘Minne-mini’ en su preparatoria,
donde alrededor de 30 equipo compiten en un día. Busca en los foros de ChiefDelphi
competencias cerca de tu área.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>
</resources>