<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!-- TAGS SHOULD BE SEPARATED BY SPACES-->

<!-- LINKS IN THE BODY TEXT SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;a href="ADDRESS">NAME&lt;/a> -->
<!-- LINE BREAKS SHOULD BE FORMATTED AS
    &lt;br> -->

<resources>
    <string-array name="fundraising_obtaining_sponsors">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Obtaining Sponsors</item>
        <item>Sponsorships often give teams large amounts of money for little effort,
            especially when compared to other methods of fundraising. Sponsors can be either
            corporate, at a major business such as JCPenny, or local, with locations that include
            a local hardware store and a restaurant. However, when obtaining sponsors it is
            important to remember that non-monetary sponsorship may be just as valuable as money.
            Many companies can offer mentorship or supply donations.
            &lt;br>The first step to getting sponsors is asking team members if any parents work for
            companies that could potentially offer money, mentors, or donations to the team. This
            option should be explored first because connections make companies much more likely to
            want to support the team. Ask the  parents for the people to contact regarding
            sponsorship at their companies, and call the contacts to schedule meetings with those
            who grant sponsorship. Once a meeting is scheduled, sponsorship is almost guaranteed.
            Prepare an interactive PowerPoint and speech, and be ready to answer questions.
            &lt;br>If no parents work at companies that could sponsor the team or additional
            sponsors are needed, there are many other options. Go to the websites of local teams and
            find out which companies sponsor them, as large companies usually sponsor several teams
            in their base areas. Local companies are also often willing to sponsor robotics teams.
            Although they might not be able to give as much money, having support from the community
            is an important aspect of FIRST.
            &lt;br>More information can be found on the
            &lt;a href="http://www.usfirst.org/roboticsprograms/first-fundraising-toolkit">FIRST Fundraising Toolkit&lt;/a>.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_obtaining_sponsorsSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Conseguir Patrocinios</item>
        <item>Los patrocinios casi siempre le otorgan a los equipos grandes cantidades de dinero por muy
poco esfuerzo, comparado con otros métodos de recaudación de fondos. Los patrocinadores
pueden ser corporativos, compañías grandes como JC Penny, o locales, como su ferretería
local o un restaurante. Sin embargo, cuando obtengas un patrocinio, es importante recordar
que apoyo no monetario puede ser igual de importante que el dinero. Muchas compañías
ofrecen mentores o proveen donaciones. El primer paso para conseguir es preguntare a sus
compañeros de equipo si trabajan en alguna compañía que pudiesen ofrecer dinero,
mentores o donaciones al equipo. Esta opción debe ser explorada primero, ya que las
conexiones hacen que las compañías estén más interesadas en apoyar al equipo. Pídanle a
los padres de familia el contacto de la persona encargada de patrocinios en la compañía, y
marquen para agendar una cita. Ya que se agendó la cita, el patrocinio está casi asegurado.
Preparen una presentación interactiva y un discurso, y estén listos para contestar preguntas.
Si ningún padre de familia trabaja en una compañía que pueda ser patrocinador o se
necesitan más patrocinadores, existen muchas otras opciones. Visiten las páginas de internet
de equipos locales y busquen cuales con las compañías que los apoyan, ya que las
compañías grandes suele apoyar a varios equipos. Las compañías locales la mayoría de las
veces están dispuestas a apoyar a equipos de robótica. Aunque no les puedan dar mucho
dinero, tener apoyo de la comunidad es un aspecto importante de FIRST-
            &lt;a href="http://www.usfirst.org/roboticsprograms/first-fundraising-toolkit">FIRST Fundraising Toolkit&lt;/a>.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_grants">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Applying for Grants</item>
        <item>Grants typically offer a one-time source of money for teams. The monetary
            amount, however, is rarely small. FIRST offers grants to its teams, but many of
            these are aimed towards and only eligible to rookie teams. Many corporations
            offer several grants to both rookie and veteran teams. At this time, these companies
            include NASA, Rockwell Automation, and PTC. Local educational foundations and
            donation-based non-profit organizations also often offer grants. When applying for
            grants, a team may apply for a general team grant or for a grant for specific, needed
            items. An example of items to buy with grant money, which may be stated when
            applying for the grant, is the purchase of computers, hard drives, and tablets.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_grantsSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Conseguir Becas</item>
        <item>Los becas casi siempre son una fuente de dinero que sólo puede ser usada una vez. La
cantidad de dinero, sin embargo, casi nunca es pequeña. FIRST ofrece becas para sus
equipos, pero están enfocadas para y sólo disponibles para equipos novatos. Muchas
corporaciones ofrecen muchas becas tanto para equipos novatos como veteranos. En este
momento, NASA, Rockwell Automation and PTC. Fundaciones educativas locales y
organizaciones sin fines de lucro también pueden ofrecer becas. Cuando apliquen para
conseguir becas, el equipo puede necesitar aplicar por becas para el equipo en general o
para materiales en específico. Un ejemplo de materiales que puedes comprar con dinero de
beca, que puede estar explícito cuando se aplique por una beca, es computadoras, discos
duros y tabletas.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_major_events">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Major Fundraising Events</item>
        <item>One reliable and consistent way to raise money is to host large fundraising events. These
            events often span several days of work and should be planned well in advance. Although a lot
            of work, these events provide an excellent way to raise funds for your team.
            &lt;br>One example of a major fundraising event is hosting a summer day camp for
            local youth. This doubles as an outreach activity because FIRST supports the introduction
            of STEAM (Science, Technology, Engineering, Art, and Mathematics) in community outreach
            to young people. Teams can charge anywhere from $50 to $250 per student for a one or two
            weeklong day camp. There are many options of concepts to teach the attending students,
            and these include MIT’s Scratch programming and robots built with Vex or FLL kit-of-parts.
            Teams can either host these camps themselves at their high school or at other community
            locations, and local “community education” groups can run and manage the camps.
            &lt;br>Teams can host school-sponsored activities to raise both money and local awareness.
            Planning and holding a themed school dance should raise anywhere from $1,000 to $5,000 per year.
            Examples of themes are winter, Valentine’s Day, and Halloween. Robotic concepts such as
            laser lights and automated decorations can even be incorporated into the dance. Students
            will be drawn to attend the dance with promotions that students DJ the music and there are
            fun, unique elements such as balloon drops.
            &lt;br>Hosting an off-season regional competition spreads awareness of the team and earns
            money. Prices to charge per attending team range from $50 to $500, and this adds up
            quickly if 20+ teams attend. Teams return continually to well-organized events because
            they provide positive networking environments for both the hosts and attendees. If a
            team is small or new to planning an event of such a large magnitude, it can team up with
            one or two other local teams and split the profits.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_major_eventsSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Eventos de Recaudación de Fondos Grandes</item>
        <item>Una manera segura y consistente de juntar dinero es organizar una recaudación de fondos.
Este tipo de eventos duran varios días y se deben de planear con tiempo. Aunque requieren
mucho trabajo, este tipo de eventos son una excelente manera de juntar fondos para su
equipo. Un excelente ejemplo de un evento de recaudación de fondos grande es organizar
un campamento para los jóvenes de su zona. Esto sirve a la vez como una actividad de
outreach ya que FIRST apoya el uso de STEAM (Science,Technology, Engineering, Arts and
Mathematics) en el outreach hacia gente joven. Los equipos pueden cobrar entre $50 y $250
por estudiante por un campamento de una o dos semanas. Hay muchas opciones de
conceptos que enseñar a los estudiante que atiendan, como el Scratch programming de MIT
así como programar y construir robots con VEX o FLL. Los equipos pueden organizar los
campamentos de manera en su escuela o en otros lugares de la comunidad, y
organizaciones locales de ‘educación de la comunidad’ pueden administrar y manejar el
campamento. Los equipos pueden organizar actividades patrocinadas por la escuela para
juntar dinero hacer propaganda. Planear y llevar a cabo un baile escolar puede ayudar a
juntar entre $1,000 y $5,000 al año. Como por ejemplo un baile de Invierno, de San Valentín
o Halloween. Conceptos que tengan que ver con robótica pueden ser incorporados al baile,
como lásers o decoraciones automatizadas. A los estudiantes les llamará la atención que
otros estudiantes estén como DJ y haya cosas como ‘balloon drops’.  Organizar un regional
fuera de temporada ayuda a promocionar el equipo y a juntar dinero. El  por equipo puedo
ser entre $50 a $500, y esto crece sobre todo si invitan a más de 20 equipos. Los equipos
regresan continuamente aventureros granizados porque proveen lugares de Networking
positivos para los organizadores y los invitados. si un equipo es pequeño o nuevo en cuanto
organización de eventos puede juntarse con algunos equipos locales y dividirse las
ganancias.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_minor_events">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Minor Fundraising Events</item>
        <item>Smaller fundraising events may raise less money, but they are easier to plan and host
            more of. Many successfully spread awareness in a team’s local community. One example is
            bagging groceries at a local supermarket. Past robots can be displayed and, if the store
            allows it, driven. Customers are usually excited to hear about the robots and community
            outreach of a FIRST team, and they are often willing to donate. This typically earns a
            team $500 to $1,500. Another small fundraising event that can be done at a supermarket
            is selling hot dogs outside the building in the summer. Local stores will often donate
            the equipment, and they will possibly donate the supplies. Watch for stores that offer
            this, and request a shift. This can make a team around $500 to $1,000. Many local and
            chain restaurants offer high school teams benefit nights. On these nights, a certain
            percentage of sales is granted to the promoted team. If a team advertises properly, it
            has the potential to earn well over $500 and into the thousands of dollars. When
            combined, these minor fundraising events can earn more money than one or two major
            events.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="fundraising_minor_eventsSpanish">
        <item>fragment_pager_item_no_image</item>
        <item>Eventos de Recaudación de Fondos Pequeños</item>
        <item>Aunque los eventos de recaudación pequeños tienen a juntar menos dinero son más fáciles
de planear y llevar acabo. Muchos generan conciencia de manera exitosa en la comunidad
del equipo. Un ejemplo de esto puede ser guardar el súper en bolsas en su supermercado
más cercano. Robots de años pasados puede ser puestos a la vista y si la tienda lo permite,
dejar los clientes lo manejen. Los clientes que siempre están emocionados al escuchar sobre
robots y ‘community outreach’ de un equipo de FIRST y casi siempre están dispuestos a
hacer una donación. Un equipo gana alrededor de $500 a $1500 en este tipo de eventos.
Otro tipo de evento de recaudación pequeña  que se pueda hacer es vender hotdogs afuera
de un supermercado cuando hace calor en el verano. Tiendas locales muchas veces donan
equipo y hasta materiales. Busquen tiendas que hagan este tipo ofertas y pidan un turno de
trabajo. Con esto, el equipo puede recaudar alrededor de $500 a $1000. Muchos
restaurantes locales y de cadena ofrecen noches de beneficio para las escuelas. En dichas
noches, un porcentaje de las ganancias se les dan al equipo que lo promociona. Sin equipo
hace una promoción adecuada, tiene potencial de ganar más de $500 o hasta los miles de
dólares. Cuando se combinan, los eventos pequeños pueden juntar más dinero que uno o
dos eventos de recaudación grandes.</item>
        <item></item>
    </string-array>

</resources>